District of Columbia Civil War Centennial Commission Records 007
People's Archive, MLK Library
District of Columbia Civil War Centennial Commission Records
1959-1966
People's Archive, MLK Library
District of Columbia Civil War Centennial Commission
007
1.5 Linear feet
4 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The District of Columbia Civil War Centennial Commission was part of the national effort to commemorate and celebrate the 100th anniversary of the American Civil War in 1961. Founded in 1959, the Commission sponsored events throughout D.C. until 1966.
Custodial History
The collection was donated by Paul J. Sedgwick, Chairman of the District of Columbia Civil War Centennial Commission.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials related to Commision planning and events; including correspondence, clippings, photographs, booklets, programs, and other memorabilia.
Armed Forces; Civil War; Centennial celebrations, etc; Photographs; Correspondence; Ephemera
- Correspondence, 1959-1965; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1965; 1.5 Linear feet
  - Correspondence, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Correspondence, 1959-1966; 1.5 Linear feet
- Clippings, 1959-1966; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1959-1966; 1.5 Linear feet
  - Clippings, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
- Ephemera, undated, 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  - Invitations to events, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Programs, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
- Centennial events photographs, 1959-1966; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1-2)
  - Awarding of centennial medals, 1961; 1.5 Linear feet
  - Events, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Events, 1959-1961; 1.5 Linear feet
  - Events, 1962; 1.5 Linear feet
  - Events, 1963-1966; 1.5 Linear feet
  - Gettysburg Address observance, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Kennedy and McCmilian, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Paul Sedgwick, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Miscellaneous events, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
- Historic photographs used in commemoration, undated, 1.5 Linear feet (Box 2)
  - Forts, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Library of Congress, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - U.S. Navy, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Brady Collection and U.S. Signal Corps, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
- Mounted Exhibit, undated, 1.5 Linear feet (Box 2)
  - Materials, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
- Oversized Materials, 1907, undated; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 3)
  - Programs, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Press releases and publicity, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Photographs, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Takoma Park: 75 Year of Community Living, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Album loose-leaf pages, undated, 1.5 Linear feet
  - Wright, Marcus T., Battles and Commanders of the Civil War, 1907; 1.5 Linear feet